Guide to the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail Architectural Records, 1883-1888 AIS.1980.20
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- H.H. Richardson's working plans for the Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail, II.
  - Section thru Tower looking West on Line GH, 35B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 2)
    County Number: 35B
    Size: 32 1/2 x 45 1/2
  - Detail of Tower, 38 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 3)
    County Number: 38
    Description: Copy of Richardson drawing #42, with modifications
    Media: Black line composite print with red & blue wash
    Size: 40 x 168
    Architect's No.: 42B
  - Section on Line PQ, 38B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 4)
    County Number: 38B
    Size: 40 x 29 3/4
    Stamped: Office of H.H. Richardson, Pittsburgh
  - Section on Line VW looking North, 41B (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 5)
    County Number: 41B
    Size: 27 3/4 x 39 1/2
    Condition: Poor; has been taped
  - Large Jail Window, 168 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 6)
    County Number: 168 (stamped on back)
    Description: Jail working drawing
    Scale: 1" = 1' - 0"
    Media: Purple line on stiff print paper, with water color wash
    Size: 20 x 52
    Condition: Poor, torn paper
  - Window Details - Guards, 169 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 7)
    County Number: 169
    Media: Purple line on print paper, color wash
    Size: 31 1/2 x 52 1/2
    Architect's No.: 26B
  - Plan of Basement, 170 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 8)
    County Number: 170
    Media: Sepia on linen, with blue ink and color wash
    Size: 34 x 35
    Architect's No.: 58
  - Large Chimney, 171 (Map-case 6-1, Folder 4, Item 9)
    County Number: 171
    Description: Jail working drawing, elevation, plan & section of chimney
    Media: black ink on linen, with color wash
    Size: 49 1/2 x 21 1/2
    Stamped: Office of Co. Engineer, March 2, 1897
    Signed: H.H. Richardson
    Architect's No.: 70
  - Entrance to Yard & Guard Room, 172 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 1)
    County Number: 172
    Description: Jail working drawings, plans, elevations & sections
    Media: Black ink on linen, with color wash
    Size: 41 x 30 1/2
    Architect's No.: 71
  - Detail of Stone Work, 173 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 2)
    County Number: 173
    Description: Jail working drawing, stone details at cornices
    Scale: 1 1/2" = 1' - 0"
    Size: 58 x 31 1/2
    Architect's No.: 72
    Condition: Poor (major staining)
  - Iron Work, 174 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 3)
    County Number: 174
    Description: Jail working drawing, plans & elevations of grilles, door into consultation room.
    Scale: 1 1/2" = 1' - 0" and as noted
    Size: 38 x 28 1/2
    Architect's No.: 75
  - Stair Case to Cells, 175 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 4)
    County Number: 175
    Media: Black ink on linen with color wash
    Size: 42 1/2" x 29 3/4"
    Stamped: March 3, 1897, County Engineer
    Architect's No.: 76
  - Ironwork, Staircase to Hospital, 176 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 5)
    County Number: 176
    Description: Jail working drawing, details of ironwork at stairs
    Scale: 1 1/2" = 1'
    Media: Black ink on linen, color wash
    Size: 40 x 28 1/2
    Stamped: March 2, 1897, County Engineer
    Architect's No.: 77
  - Basement Floor NW, 750 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 6)
    County Number: 750
    Media: Black ink on linen, red & blue dimensions & color wash
    Size: 31 1/4 x 42
  - Basement Floor SW, 751 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 7)
    County Number: 751
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue brown, red dimensions, color wash
    Size: 31 x 42
    Architect's No.: 2
    Condition: Poor, torn, (taped top left)
  - Basement Floor SE, 752 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 5, Item 8)
    County Number: 752
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue, brown, red dimensions, color wash
    Size: 31 1/2 x 41 1/2
  - Basement Floor NE, 753 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 1)
    County Number: 753
    Media: Black ink on linen, brown, blue, red dimensions, color wash
    Size: 31 x 41 1/2
  - First Floor NW, 754 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 2)
    County Number: 754
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, with penciled revisions
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue, brown, red dimensions & color wash
    Size: 31 x 42 1/2
    Condition: Poor (stains)
  - First Floor SW, 755 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 3)
    County Number: 755
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue dimensions & color wash
    Size: 31 1/2 x 43
    Condition: Poor, stained
  - First Floor SE, 756 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 4)
    County Number: 756
    Size: 31 1/2 x 42 1/2
    Stamped: Office of County Engineering, March 2, 1897
    Condition: Poor, (stain)
  - First Floor NE, 757 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 5)
    County Number: 757
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan. Clerk of Courts, Treasurer's Office, Sheriff's Office.
    Size: 311/2 x 43
    Condition: Poor, (stained)
  - First Floor Mezzanine NW, 758 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 1)
    County Number: 758
    Size: 31 x 39
  - First Floor Mezzanine SW, 759 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 2)
    County Number: 759
    Size: 31 x 39 1/2
    Condition: Poor, stained & torn
  - First Floor Mezzanine SE, 760 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 6, Item 3)
    County Number: 760
    Size: 31 1/2 x 39
    Condition: Fair, stained
  - First Floor Mezzanine NE, 761 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 1)
    County Number: 761
    Size: 40 1/2 x 31
  - Second Floor NW, 762 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 2)
    County Number: 762
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plans of Court of Common Pleas, Supreme Court, & Law Library
    Size: Not Available
    Stamped: County Engineering, March 2, 1897
  - Second Floor NW, 763 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 3)
    County Number: 763
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan of Orphans & Common Pleas Courts
    Size: 31 x 41
    Architect's No.: 14
  - Second Floor SE, 764 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 4)
    County Number: 764
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan of Criminal Courts & Orphans Court
    Size: 31 x 40
    Architect's No.: 15
  - Second Floor NE, 765 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 5)
    County Number: 765
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan of Common Pleas, Large Criminal Court
    Stamped: County Engineer, March 2, 1897
    Condition: Poor (not bad)
  - Second Floor Mezzanine NW, 766 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 6)
    County Number: 766
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plans of Common Pleas Jury
    Size: 31 1/2 x 41
    Architect's No.: 17
  - Second Floor Mezzanine SW, 767 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 7)
    County Number: 767
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Common Pleas Jury
    Architect's No.: 18
  - Second Floor Mezzanine SE, 768 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 8)
    County Number: 768
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Criminal Pleas Jury & Orphan Court Judge's Chambers
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue & red dimensions, color wash
  - Second Floor Mezzanine NE, 769 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 7, Item 9)
    County Number: 769
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Common Pleas Jury, Criminal Court Jury
    Size: 31 1/2 x 42
    Condition: Poor, stained, (tear through signature)
  - Third Floor NW, 770 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8)
    County Number: 770
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Country Engineer, Prothonotarys Trans. Room, Clerk of Supreme Court
    Stamped: March 2, 1897 County Eng.; C/17-5
    Condition: Poor, (stained orange brown)
  - Third Floor SW, 771 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 1)
    County Number: 771
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Grand Jury, Coroner, Recorder
    Media: Black ink on linen, red & blue dimensions & color wash, pencil
    Size: 32 1/2 x 40
    Stamped: C/17-5
    Condition: Fair, (taped "girder chart")
  - Third Floor SE, 772 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 2)
    County Number: 772
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, District Attorney, Commissioner's Trans. Room
    Media: Black ink on linen, red & blue dimensions, color wash, pencil
    Size: 38 1/2 x 31
    Architect's No.: 23
    Condition: Poor, (stain, ink spot)
  - Third Floor NE, 773 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 3)
    County Number: 773
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, plan, Clerk of Court, Country Superintendent
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue dimensions, color wash, pencil
    Size: 30 1/2 x 38 1/2
    Architect's No.: 24
  - Attic Plan, 774 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 4)
    County Number: 774
    Media: Black ink on linen, dimensions
    Size: 36 x 40
    Architect's No.: 25
  - Roof Plan, 775 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 5)
    County Number: 775
    Size: 35 x 43
    Architect's No.: 26
  - Grant Street Elevation - Facade Front, 776 (Map-case 6-10, Folder 8, Item 6)
    County Number: 776
    Description: Courthouse blueprint
    Media: blueprint
    Size: 37 1/2 x 47
    Signed: H.H. Richardson (on original)
    Architect's No.: 27
  - Courthouse Fifth Avenue, 777 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 7)
    County Number: 777
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, elevation
    Media: Black ink on linen, pencil
    Size: 37 1/2 x 50
    Architect's No.: 28
    Condition: Poor, (missing large section on top)
  - Ross Street Elevation, 778 (Map-case 6-2, Folder 8, Item 8)
    County Number: 778
    Size: 33 x 51
    Architect's No.: 29
  - Forbes Street Elevation, 779 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 1)
    County Number: 779
    Size: 44 x 50
    Architect's No.: 30
    Condition: Fair, (stained, fragile), not encapsulated
  - Section on Center-Line A-B, 780 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 2)
    County Number: 780
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, section west looking south
    Media: Black ink on linen, color wash and pencil
    Stamped: March 2, 1897 County Engineer
    Architect's No.: 31
    Condition: Poor (original & copy), corner falling off original, not encapsulated
  - Section on Center-Line C-D, 781 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 3)
    County Number: 781
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, east looking south
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue ink and color wash
    Size: 43 x 46
    Architect's No.: 32
    Condition: Poor, stained left upper corner, not encapsulated
  - Section on Line E-F, 782 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 1)
    County Number: 782
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, section north looking east
    Media: Black ink on linen, red dimensions and color wash
    Size: 38 x 58
    Architect's No.: 33
    Condition: Fair, (top corners are torn)
  - Section through Tower Looking West on Line G-H, 783 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 2)
    County Number: 783
    Size: 34 x 43
    Architect's No.: 34
  - Section on Line I-K, 784 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 3)
    County Number: 784
    Architect's No.: 35
  - Section in Line L-M, 785 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 4)
    County Number: 785
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, Section looking toward court
    Size: 24 x 29
    Architect's No.: 36
  - Section on line N-O, 786 (Map-case 6-10, Folder 9, Item 5)
    blueprint
    County Number: 786
    Description: Courthouse blueprint, Section looking toward tower
    Media: Cyanotype
    Size: 17 1/2 x 29
    Stamped: March 2, 1897 Co. Eng. (on original)
    Architect's No.: 37
  - Section on line P-Q, 787 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 6)
    County Number: 787
    Description: Courthouse blueprint, Section south looking west
    Size: 29 x 40
    Architect's No.: 38
  - Section on line R-S, 788 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 4)
    County Number: 788
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, Section southwest looking south
    Size: 43 x 50
    Architect's No.: 39
    Condition: Poor, (large stains), not encapsulated
  - Section Through SE Pavilion on line T-U, 789 (Oversize Tabletop, Folder 22, Item 5)
    County Number: 789
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, section looking south
    Media: Black ink on linen, red ink, color wash
    Size: 42 x 58
    Stamped: March 2, 1897, County Eng.
    Architect's No.: 40
    Condition: Poor (large stain), not encapsulated
  - Section on line V-W, 790 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 7)
    County Number: 790
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, Section looking north
    Size: 29 x 40 1/2
    Architect's No.: 41
  - Detail of Pavilion, 792 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 8)
    County Number: 792
    Media: Black composite print with red & blue wash
    Size: 40 x ?
    Architect's No.: 43
  - Interior Elevation of Pavilion Windows & Detail, 793 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 9)
    County Number: 793
    Size: 36 x 47 1/2
    Architect's No.: 44
    Condition: Poor, (stain on back, possibly mold)
  - Wrought Iron Gates, 794 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 10)
    County Number: 794
    Description: Courthouse working drawing, wrought iron gates at Delivery Entrance & Ross St. Entrance Court House
    Scale: 3/4"
    Size: 32 x 39
    Architect's No.: 45
    Condition: Fair, (stains, possibly from mold)
  - Wooden Mantels and Iron Book-Racks, 795 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 9, Item 11)
    County Number: 795
    Scale: 1 1/2"
    Size: 30 1/2 x 40 1/2
    Architect's No.: 46
    Condition: Fair, (stains)
  - Corner Staircase, 796 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 1)
    County Number: 796
    Size: 30 x 41 1/2
    Architect's No.: 47
    Condition: Poor, (stains)
  - Ross Street Entrance, Wainscot, 797 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 2)
    County Number: 797
    Size: 26 1/2 x 42 1/2
    Architect's No.: 48
  - Framing of Roof, 798 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 3)
    County Number: 798
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue dimensions
    Size: 33 1/2 x 43
    Architect's No.: 49
  - Roof Framing, Section Through Roof, 799 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 4)
    County Number: 799
    Architect's No.: 50
  - Details -- Detail of Brownstone Nosing of Gallery, 800 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 5)
    County Number: 800
    Size: 27 x 42
    Architect's No.: 51
  - Plan and Sections of Tunnel Under Ross Street, 801 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 6)
    County Number: 801
    Size: 26 x 29
    Architect's No.: 52
  - Item 3 as modified -- Slate Base to Marble Wainscot, 802 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 7)
    County Number: 802
    Size: 15 1/2 x 29
    Architect's No.: 53
  - Grand Staircase -- First Floor Plan, 803 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 10, Item 8)
    County Number: 803
    Media: Black ink on linen, red dimensions, color wash
    Size: 48 x 33
  - Grand Staircase, 804 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 1)
    County Number: 804
    Media: Black ink on linen, red ink, color wash, pencil
    Size: 35 x 52
    Stamped: Recd., Aug. 21, 1886
    Architect's No.: 140A
  - Grand Staircase, 805 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 2)
    County Number: 805
    Size: 38 x 41 1/2
    Stamped: Rcd., August 21, 1886
    Architect's No.: 141
  - Grand Staircase, 806 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 3)
    County Number: 806
    Size: 32 x 43 1/2
    Architect's No.: 142
  - Grand Staircase, 807 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 4)
    County Number: 807
    Architect's No.: 143
  - Grand Staircase, 808 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 5)
    County Number: 808
    Media: black ink on linen, red ink, color wash
    Size: 36 x 44
    Stamped: Recd. August
    Architect's No.: 144A
  - Grand Staircase, 809 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 6)
    County Number: 809
    Size: 31 x 51
    Architect's No.: 145A
  - Courthouse -- Framing of Roof, 810 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 7)
    County Number: 810
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue ink
    Size: 22 1/2 x 40 1/2
    Stamped: Office of H.H. Richardson
    Architect's No.: 45B
  - Roof Framing and Trusses, 811 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 11, Item 8)
    County Number: 811
    Size: 28 x 40
    Architect's No.: 46B
  - Sections of Roof for New Courthouse Turret, 812 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 1)
    County Number: 812
    Size: 23 x 29
  - Sections of Courthouse Roof - Turrets, 813 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 2)
    County Number: 813
    Size: 25 1/2 x 29
  - Courthouse Roof - Trusses, 814 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 3)
    County Number: 814
    Size: 30 x 44
  - Plan of Foundation Alteration No. 4, 815 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 4)
    County Number: 815
    Size: 36 x 48
    Architect's No.: 83C
  - Block Plan and Retaining Walls of Courthouse, 816 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 5)
    County Number: 816
    Media: Black ink on linen, blue and red ink, color wash
    Size: 36 x 55
    Signed: Approved Jan. 19, 1886, F.E. Alden
    Architect's No.: 82
  - Alteration No. 4, Item V, 3985 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 6)
    County Number: 3985
    Media: Black ink on linen, red dimensions
    Size: 15 1/8 x 22 1/4
    Condition: Good, (holes in bottom right corner)
  - Jail Longitudinal, 4648 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 12, Item 7)
    County Number: 4648
    Description: Jail working drawing, section
    Size: 34 x 21 1/2
  - Sections and corners of blgds. (interior and exterior), 4649 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 1)
    County Number: 4649
    Size: 35 x 24 3/4
    Stamped: Office of H.H. Richardson, Pittsburgh, PA
    Condition: Poor, (torn corner)
  - Alterations #6 Sections A-B, C-D, G-H, L-M, N-O, received April 13, 1885, by C.D.; 4650 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 2)
    County Number: 4650
    Media: Paper print with color added
    Size: 34 x 21 3/4
  - Trusses - roof & roof of bridge tower and of guard room, 4651 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 3)
    County Number: 4651
    Description: Jail working drawing, trusses of Guard Room roof
    Size: 30 x 23
    Architect's No.: 85
  - Trusses, Rec'd Jan. 4, 1886 by Chas. Davis; 4652 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 4)
    County Number: 4652
    Description: Jail working drawing, trusses at bridge tower roof
  - Bridge over Ross Street, 4653 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 5)
    County Number: 4653
    Size: 38 x 23
    Architect's No.: 100C
  - Arches in Jail Wall over Railroad Tunnel, Alteration No. 5, 4654 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 6)
    County Number: 4654
    Description: Jail working drawing, Alteration #5
    Size: 35 x 22
  - Elevation & Plans of Jail Yard and Wall, etc., 4655 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 7)
    County Number: 4655
    Architect: Not Available
    Description: Jail working drawing; probably not a Richardson drawing
    Size: 35 x 24
  - Interior Finish in Administration Building, 4657 (Map-case 6-3, Folder 13, Item 8)
    County Number: 4657
    Description: Jail working drawing. Mantels & Doors in Jailor's Office & Apartments & Hospital.
    Scale: 1 1/2" = 1' 0"
    Size: 35 x 23
    Architect's No.: 78
  - Elevation of Windows, 5642 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 1)
    County Number: 5642
    Description: Courthouse shop drawing
    Size: 28 1/2 x 35 1/2
    Signed: L.M. Morris, Norcross Brothers, Pittsburgh, August 4, 1886
  - Elevations of Windows, 5643 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 2)
    County Number: 5643
    Media: Black ink on linen, red & blue ink
    Size: 28 1/2 x 36 1/2
  - Elevations of Windows, 5644 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 3)
    County Number: 5644
    Size: 28 3/4 x 35 1/4
  - Elevations of Windows, 5645 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 4)
    County Number: 5645
    Size: 30 1/4 x 35 1/4
    Condition: Poor, (tears on edges, "Sec. C" written on back is bleeding through)
  - Plan of Hot Air Ducts in Basement, 7100 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 5)
    County Number: 7100
    Size: 23 3/4 x 13
    Stamped: received January 5, 1885 by Chas Davis
    Architect's No.: 38C
  - Alterations of Sections C-D, E-F, G-H, 7101 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 6)
    County Number: 7101
    Size: 16 3/4 x 22 1/2
    Stamped: received January 5, 1885 Chas Davis
    Architect's No.: 39C
  - Alteration of Front Elevation, 7102 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 7)
    County Number: 7102
    Size: 19 1/4 x 15 1/2
    Stamped: received January 5, 1885 Chas. Davis
    Architect's No.: 40C
  - Framing Plan of Boiler Room, 7103 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 14, Item 8)
    County Number: 7103
    Size: 18 1/2 x 16 1/2
    Architect's No.: 43G
  - Alteration of Section A-B, 7104 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 1)
    County Number: 7104
    Size: 21 3/4 x 12 1/4
    Architect's No.: 44C
  - Corner Gutter for Jail, 7109 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 2)
    County Number: 7109
    Description: Jail shop drawing, Alteration #8. Freehand drawing - perhaps by Richardson
    Scale: full scale
    Size: 20 1/2 x 18
    Stamped: received October 15, 1885
  - Plan -- Electric Light Plant for Courthouse & Jail, 2/20/1888; 7110 (Map-case 6-4, Folder 15, Item 3)
    County Number: 7110
    Architect: Shepley, Rutan & Coolidge
    Description: Courthouse & Jail shop drawing
    Size: 25 x 18
    Stamped: U.S. Electric Light Co. New York, 2/13/1888, L.H.
    Signed: R.E. Mercer, Geo. Y. McKee, Daniel McWilliams
- Alterations and Additions to Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail, III.
  This series includes blueprints used by other architects to make additions or alterations to Richardson's courthouse and jail after it was erected. Included are plans by Frederick Osterling; Frank E. Alden and Alfred Harlow; construction engineer Charles Good; and General Foreman of Mechanics for Allegheny County, I.A. Lawrence.
  - Alterations to Jail & Mech. Equip., 1919 (Map-case 6, Folder 23, Item 7)
    Architect: Alden & Harlow
    Description: later jail modifications
    Size: 30 x 42
  - First Floor, 1939; CH A-1 (Map-case 6, Folder 23, Item 8)
    County Number: CH A-1
    Architect: I.A. Lawrence, Gen'l Foreman of Mechanics, Allegheny County
    Description: remodeling drawing
    Media: reduced photostat
  - Second Floor, 1939; CH A-2 (Map-case 6, Folder 23, Item 9)
    County Number: CH A-2
  - Alterations & Additions to Jail (Map-case 6, Folder 24, Item 1-2)
    Architect: Osterling
    Description: structural framing plans & details
  - Alterations & Additions to Jail (Map-case 6, Folder 24, Item 3)
    Description: basement heating & ventilating
  - Roof Plan of New Eaves, 1948 (Map-case 6, Folder 24, Item 4)
    Architect: Charles Good, Cons't Eng.
    Description: Jail renovation plan